Gordon: This season
on "MasterChef,"
we are making history...
- Oh, my God!
- ...because for
the first time ever,
we'll have partners
in the kitchen.
Husbands and wives,
mothers and daughters,
- best friends,
even divorced couples.
- Give her a nice kiss.
- This is "MasterChef:
Dynamic Duos."
- We're here, baby!
This season we will crown
two MasterChefs.
- We have the best chemistry.
- We are here to take the title.
- And who's in charge?
- We fight over that
a little bit, but--
- Me!
- Joe and myself will be joined
by a brand new judge...
Tiffany Derry! Oh, yes!
This competition
is going to be fierce.
...to find out if two cooks
really are better than one.
They are like
synchronized swimmers.
- Come on.
- The dynamic in this
duo has disappeared.
Was not my call, Chef.
It was his call.
You need you need to own
your partner's decision.
I'm doing my best.
Just calm down.
We are doubling the difficulty
with new challenges...
This is only possible
as a dynamic duo.
Ten minutes, ten minutes,
ten minutes, ten minutes. Sold!
We're gonna play
recipe telephone.
Me and Kayla
are telepathic twins.
Come on! Sauce!
Time for the big swap.
Are you ready?
Cait, the sauce!
- Lift!
- ...and some familiar
favorites.
The return of the dreaded
pressure test.
- Get it, get it, get it.
Where is it?
- You grab it. Right there.
- Wow, the wall.
- We want identical plates.
- Do you hear me?
- I can't.
- Jess, two piece asparagus!
- I can't hear you!
- ( whistle blowing )
- Oh, my God!
It'll take all they've got
to stay on track...
- We have to start plating!
- We got an overcooked duck.
- Oh, my God.
- This is a freaking
train wreck.
- Holy ( bleep ).
- Whoo!
...and weather every storm.
- This weather is crazy!
- We're not ( bleep ) around.
- I want to get off this ride.
- You're going home.
- Oh, hey, medic! Medic!
- ( wheezing )
But the duo that proves
they're dynamic enough...
- This is Michelin star
chef's plating.
- Yes!
- This is explosive.
- Thank you so much.
I really see the dynamic duo.
You've got
the marriage right here.
A bit like you two.
...will share the ultimate
culinary prize.
- Together you're
cooking like pros.
- Oh, my God.
- As a duo, this is the level
you need to be at.
- Thank you, Chef.
- This is better than some
of my restaurants.
- Oh, Joe!
You may kiss the bride.
This is "MasterChef:
Dynamic Duos."
I don't like cooking
without you.
( cheering )
MasterChef! Here we are!
- There it is! There it is!
- Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
Let's go!
Oh, my gosh.
- Oh, wow.
- It's so pretty.
- We're here!
Can you believe it?
- I can't believe it.
- Let's go!
- Come on!
- We're here.
- Oh, my God!
- I feel so emotional.
Can you believe it?
- I know.
We love cooking together.
So when we found out
that this season
- we're gonna be together...
- It was like the dream
come true for us.
I can't believe
that we're here.
This is my partner in life
and in the kitchen.
- This is what
we've been training for.
- We're cooking all off.
And this is what we want to do
for the rest of our lives.
- Dude, I'm just happy to
be here doing this with you.
- This is gonna be awesome.
- Yeah, man. You, too.
- Inside those doors
is our dream.
- Mm-hmm.
- I'm like, where's Gordon?
- ( shrieking )
- Whoa.
Gordon: Let's go.
( screaming, cheering )
- ( cheering continues )
- Gordon: I'm excited.
Oh, my goodness me.
Welcome, everybody,
to our incredible 15th season
of "MasterChef."
- Yeah!
- ( cheering )
- Oh, my God.
- But listen up.
"MasterChef" has always
been about finding
- America's best home cook.
- Oh, yeah.
But this year we want to
highlight the power of partners
in the kitchen.
For the first time
in "MasterChef" history,
we will crown not one,
but two MasterChefs.
- How cool is that?
- Baby, right here!
This is "MasterChef:
Dynamic Duos."
( cheering )
- Yes! Yes! Yes!
- Whoo!
We have brought the best duos
from all across America
here to the amazing
MasterChef kitchen.
And trust me,
we have everything
from husbands and wives.
- Yeah!
- To mothers and daughters,
- aunts and nieces. Yes?
- Yeah!
Best friends.
- Even co-workers.
- Whoo!
Amazing!
We even have
a divorced couple?
- Happily! Happily!
- Amazing.
Look at the distance
between you two still.
- Closer together.
- Give a nice kiss.
It's gonna be interesting
watching you two cook.
And, young lady,
you are hyperventilating--
in the yellow, yes?
- Yes, that's right.
- Why now?
We've said forever that that
once there was a partner season
that we would be there.
So here we are.
Glad to hear it.
And who's in charge?
- We fight over that
a little bit.
- Me, me!
- Wow.
- Well, here's the thing, guys,
even though you're competing
as a duo, we're not going
to be judging as a duo.
This season we'll be joined
by a new judge.
- Wow.
- Ooh!
Someone that is no stranger
to the MasterChef kitchen.
- She...
- Oh, it's a woman!
...is a decorated chef
with nearly 30 years
of culinary experience.
Oh, my God. Who's that?
And like us, she has her own
culinary empire.
- Now, are you ready
to meet her?
- Yes!
- Here she comes.
- Oh!
( chattering, cheering )
Wow!
Oh, my God.
- Who's it gonna be?
- Please give a warm welcome
to the amazing...
- Tiffany Derry!
- ( cheering )
Tiffany is an incredible,
world-renowned,
award-winning chef,
a celebrated restaurateur,
and a true culinary icon
of the South.
We are so lucky to have her
join the MasterChef family.
- Oh, man!
Good to see you, darling.
- How are you?
- Welcome.
- Oh, my God!
Wow. How cool is this to have
Tiffany Derry as our new judge?
- Come on, give it up.
- Yeah!
- ( cheering )
- Tiffany, welcome
to the MasterChef family.
- Thank you.
What a pleasure and an honor
to have you here.
Now tell us a little bit
how you worked your way
through the culinary ranks.
Give us an insight to
the beginning of that journey.
I started as a server.
At 16, I was managing.
And now to be able
to own your own,
I think is one of the most
beautiful things about spreading
love and great food.
- Love that. Love that!
- ( cheering )
Right. On to the reason
why you're all here.
Listen up because at the end
of this competition,
the best duo will earn
the title, the trophy,
and a quarter
of a million dollars.
Right here!
You've got the winners
right here.
But you may think that competing
as duos could be easier.
But trust me, this season
is gonna be twice as tough.
Because tonight, to earn
your spot in the competition,
you'll face off in a battle
against another duo.
- Ooh.
- It's a battle you need to win
to get your hands
on two of these.
- Woohoo!
- That's right.
The incredible MasterChef apron.
- Whoo!
- Yeah!
My name on it.
In these audition battles,
two duos will enter
the MasterChef kitchen,
- but only one duo
will leave with aprons.
- Oh.
And you're gonna have
just 30 minutes on the clock.
- Oh, man.
- Gordon: Right.
it's time for our first duos
to battle it out
to get their hands on
that coveted MasterChef apron.
All of you,
the very best of luck.
- We'll see you in the kitchen.
- Thank you.
( music playing )
Wow, this is gonna be
so exciting.
- I cannot wait to cook.
- Oh, my God.
- I need my apron, Javier.
- Ah!
- If you don't give me
my apron, Javier--
- Yes. No, no, no.
- You got it. Don't worry.
- Half of us are
getting an apron.
- That's insane.
- Gordon on PA: Right.
First up,
Jesse and Jessica...
- Oh!
...versus
Michelle and Zach.
( cheering )
J-Squared!
Oh, my God.
- Oh, my God!
- Jesse: We don't want to live
that straightforward
9 to 5 life anymore.
Once we get the apron,
we're not looking back.
We are here to be
the next MasterChefs.
- Come on down. Come on down.
- Hi!
Now tell us who you are
and what the relationship
is between this dynamic duo.
I'm Zach. This is Michelle.
We're from Minneapolis,
Minnesota.
- We've been married
for four years.
- Yeah.
- Watching "MasterChef" for 15.
- Yes.
Big, big, big fans
of "MasterChef."
It essentially
brought us together
and probably
why we're married today.
- Love that.
- And?
We're J-Squared.
My name is Jesse.
This is my beautiful
partner Jessica.
- And we are
New England foodies.
- Nice.
Okay, you are now
fighting for a spot
in the MasterChef kitchen, guys.
- We're ready. Yeah.
- Let's go.
Okay, your 30 minutes
starts now.
- Whoo!
- Let's go.
- Let's go, baby.
- All right. Ingredients.
- All right, we're heating oil.
- Yup.
- Doing it baby.
We're doing it.
- We're doing this.
What are we looking
for in this season of duos?
I'm looking for the bond.
I'm looking for the trust.
And more importantly,
communication, right?
- I love you.
- I love you, too.
- Two tablespoons of sugar,
babe? Two tablespoons sugar?
- Yes. Yep.
But also what they put on
the plate should be exceptional
because it's two phenomenal
- amateur chefs
coming in as one.
- Yeah.
All right, let's go.
We got to get going
on the chicken.
- Let's go.
- Zach and Michelle.
Give us an insight
to the dish, please.
Yeah, this is a chili spice
chicken leg quarter
on top of a parmesan
- mascarpone polenta.
- Love that.
And is this a dish you would
cook for a dinner party?
We've got a one-year-old
at home, so the dinner parties
have kind of taken
a little bit of a dip lately.
- Congrats. How'd you meet?
- We were friends first.
Met through a friend group.
And eventually
we realized, "Wait a second.
I think I love you."
- "I think I love you, too."
- Gordon: You think?
- Really? Yeah.
- Love that.
So we're coming up
to 10 minutes down with
20 minutes to go.
- Whoo!
- Jessica and Jesse,
what are you cooking?
A crispy skin salmon served
with an aji verde Peruvian green
sauce and pickled fresnos.
- Oh, love that idea.
- Wow!
- Yeah!
- Love that.
How'd you guys meet?
We actually used to bartend
next to each other in Boston.
And there was a lot
of dancing around each other,
and then that dancing
ended up progressing,
- and here we are
eight years later.
- Wow.
Nice. Looks good, looks good.
- Nice, nice. All right.
- So, Zack and Michelle's
chicken,
- it sounds delicious.
- Yeah, yeah.
Especially that
lovely creamy polenta.
Also I love seeing
the chicken thigh and--
- It's what I was about to say.
- Yeah.
Is there jeopardy in a half hour
of properly cooking
- a complete
chicken leg and thigh?
- There's-- yeah. Absolutely.
- Yeah, you got your work
cut out there.
- Mm-hmm.
- All right oven open.
- Yep. Chicken going in.
- Yep.
It's going in. All right.
- Love it.
Beautiful.
- You make this in your sleep.
- Yep. Nice.
The salmon dish
with Jesse and Jessica,
it sounds intriguing.
Yeah,
it sounds punchy, flavorful.
- I like the Peruvian accents.
- And I love a crispy skin.
Any. I mean, salmon,
love to see that technique.
But the technique about
searing the salmon is very,
very important.
- So they're kind of pushing it.
- How does the skin look, baby?
- Tell me how it feels.
- Yeah, that feels crispy.
- Okay, yep.
- Looking good, looking good.
- Thanks.
- Tell me what you think
and taste the seasoning.
Both couples are non-stop
talking, communicating, tasting.
- Yes.
- Needs a little salt, I think.
- Needs a little salt?
- Yep.
- 15 minutes gone.
15 minutes remaining.
- Whoa.
Remember only two aprons up
for grabs for one dynamic duo.
You do not want to go home
empty-handed.
- Heard.
- Let's go.
- Need to get that sauce going,
babycakes.
- Yep. I'm almost there.
- Ooh, babycakes.
- Say nice things
like that to me.
- You got it, babycakes.
Where's that meat thermometer?
- Jessica, Jesse! J-Squared!
- Jesse: How are you?
- How we doing?
- How much longer?
Give it quick little temp,
but I think we're looking
pretty good.
- What did you season it with?
- Salt and pepper.
Heavy on the salt and pepper.
Baby, want to feel this for me?
- Yep.
- Feel good.
- You know what I love
about you guys working?
- It feels great.
Everything, y'all double check
with each other.
- Jesse: Yes, yes.
- Absolutely.
- Like a true team.
- Yes, yes.
I seen you force fed him
some broccolini.
I force feed him all the time.
All the time.
- Right?
- You know what to do.
You opened up.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's natural, right?
To sit here
and go through that?
It's awesome.
Y'all looking good.
Good job y'all.
- Jessica:
Beautiful. Thank you.
- Hot open, hot open.
How we feeling
about those tomatoes?
- Are they a little over?
- No.
I am concerned
about this polenta.
The water's not boiling yet.
The stock's not boiling.
- Gordon: No.
- Come on, polenta. Come on.
Michelle, is that polenta on?
- It's not on yet.
About to do that right now.
- Please.
- I got it. I got it.
- Please, please, please.
I would throw the polenta
on in the beginning
- because waiting is not
gonna make it any better.
- No.
- ( sighs )
- What's up?
The polenta. Let's go.
Let's go. Let's go. Let's go.
- Get it going!
- They're nervous.
- They're nervous for us?
- Where's the polenta?
We just need
to say some prayers.
Damn. It's gonna be hard
to get flavor there now.
I hope it's boiling.
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
Come on.
- All right,
we're almost boiling here.
- Michelle: Okay.
- Get it going.
- I'm gonna need you
for a taste.
- Polenta going in.
- Okay. Polenta in.
- Lime... salt.
- ( bleep ) delicious.
- Is it?
- It's so good. It's so good.
Oh, that's so good.
Whew!
All right, there we go.
10 minutes remaining. Right,
how's that chicken, please?
- It's gonna be great.
- Yeah? Crank up the oven, okay?
- Make sure they're on.
- 450, 450.
How come that polenta
went on late?
- I know. Time flies.
- What are you doing time?
- Congratulations on
that baby, by the way.
- Thank you so much.
Normally someone's at home
always looking after,
but both of you being here
this far away,
- how're you coping?
- It's been hard.
Yeah. You know?
We're not gonna lie about that.
But he's well cared for,
and we're showing him that
you got to chase your dreams
- and this is what we're doing.
- Good.
Make sure that chicken's good.
Get flavor in that polenta.
- We will. Yep.
You got it. Thank you.
- Good luck.
- Looks great.
- Beautiful. Nice and crispy.
- All right, chicken.
- Looks good.
- All right, let's go!
- How do you feel?
- Good? That good?
- That's the sauce, babe.
Two minutes to go.
Start plating.
Here we go.
This is all happening right now.
Get in there. Pour it on there.
Pour it on there. Come on.
Come on, guys.
Finishing touches now. Come on.
Yeah, this is gonna be
the prettiest part.
- Looking delicious, babe.
- Thanks.
- Come on. This little chunk.
- Oh.
- Woohoo-hoo-hoo!
- Five, four, three, two, one.
- And stop. Hands in the air.
- High-five, high-five.
- ( squeals )
- Gordon: Well done.
Okay, Zach and Michelle,
please present your dish.
Michelle: We have for you a
chili-spiced chicken leg quarter
on top of creamy mascarpone
parmesan polenta,
blistered tomatoes, and topped
with an anchovy breadcrumb.
It looks beautiful.
I love the color on the chicken.
I was nervous,
the fact that it wasn't
gonna be cooked in time,
but you've proved me
wrong there.
Polenta still not on
with 10 minutes to go,
that's that's quite a scary
area, but it looks so inviting.
- Really well done.
- Thank you.
How long was the chicken
in there for?
About 20 minutes?
Gordon:
Chicken is cooked beautifully.
Tiffany:
When Gordon was cutting
into the chicken,
there was a moment
where my mouth watered.
I said,
"Ooh, that chicken look juicy!"
- That chicken is delicious.
- Aah!
Gosh, you got the flavor
on that chicken,
and you did it in such
a small amount of time.
- Thank you.
- Thank you, Chef. Thank you.
The polenta's creamy.
Beautifully seasoned.
- Really good job.
- Thank you. Thank you, Chef.
Chicken is juicy.
Maybe almost too juicy somehow.
- What? Never!
- A word no one has ever said.
- I'll take it.
- Yeah, we'll take that.
But an excellent--
an excellent dish.
- Thank you.
- Thank you, Joe.
Good job, guys.
- Well, we did good.
- Yeah.
The double J,
Jessica and Jesse.
- J-Squared!
Jesse: What you have
in front of you tonight
is a crispy skin salmon
with roasted broccolini
served with the aji verde
Peruvian green sauce
and some pickled fresnos.
It's rare to have the courage
to not put carbs or starches
on a plate because you have
nothing to fall back on,
and it's really about
the technique and the flavors.
Aside from that,
it looks perfect.
- Thank you.
- Thank you
Jesse, the temperature
on the salmon, what were
you looking for?
We're looking for
a little bit of medium rare
inside of there.
Mm. It's pink.
It looks beautiful.
- The dish tastes as good
as it looks. Exceptional.
- Thank you.
What I love here is you got that
powerful umami bomb underneath
- that just tantalizes
the palate. Well done.
- Thank you.
The salmon itself
is unbelievable.
I do think you could have seared
it just a little bit longer.
But, I mean, gosh,
it is-- it's good.
- Thank you.
- Thank you. Thank you so much.
The dish has great points
of acidity.
The broccolini is crunchy
and soft at the same time.
Excellent dish.
- Both: Thank you.
- Thank you.
Appreciate it.
Now we're faced
with the toughest decision
because nobody deserves
to fly home.
- Excuse us.
- Whew. Good job.
- Zach and Michelle's chicken.
- Joe: Well-executed.
- Well-thought out dish.
- Yeah.
I feel like
I'm going to throw up.
The JJ salmon dish
was also really good.
Halfway through that tasting
across both dishes,
I had to remind myself
they're amateurs.
We're talking to them like pros.
- We did everything
in our power.
- I know. I know.
So we're in agreement then?
- Yeah.
- Good.
( sighs )
All four of you really
showed us the love tonight.
But one of these duos
just edged out the others.
These aprons go to...
One of these duos
just edged out the others.
These aprons go to...
( indistinct chatter )
- Ah!
- Here we go, here we go,
here we go.
- ( gasping )
- ( screaming )
Yes! Yes!
( screaming )
Michelle: It's hard
to be here away from our son,
but he's gonna be
so proud of us.
He's gonna see that he can do
anything that he wants,
he can chase his dreams,
because he saw us do it.
And it means so much
to us to be here,
to be together.
It's just a dream come true.
We're so lucky to be here.
- Love you.
- Love you, too.
Jessica:
We want this so badly.
So to have that
snatched away from us
was absolutely devastating.
We feel disappointed,
not in our cook, by any means.
Just the results.
Jessica: We did everything
that we possibly could.
I just hate
losing talent like that.
I hate it.
To send somebody home
that cooked like that?
- Oh, my goodness me.
That was tough.
- ( Joe groans )
Gordon on PA: Right.
Next up, Aivan and Tina...
Hello!
...versus Asa and Shanda.
Oh, yeah! Let's go, baby!
- Let's go, baby!
- Aivan: I'm so excited
to showcase our culture,
heritage,
flavors to the judges.
And, Gordon,
you better give me an apron
- because I'm here for it!
- She's gonna come take it.
- Oh, my God. Yay!
- Welcome.
Shanda:
Not getting an apron?
Not an option.
We came here to compete.
We came here to win.
We got our entire family
on our back.
So it's a lot of pressure,
but we're here to do it.
- Hello, hello!
- I love it.
All right,
tell us who you are.
- Introduce yourself.
- I'm Tina. I'm 63 years old.
I'm a retired fishing boat owner
and this is my niece.
Yup. I'm Aivan,
I'm 32 years old,
and I'm a general contractor.
All right,
who we have over here?
My name is Shanda
and this is my cousin Asa,
and we come from
a family of chefs.
- Wow.
So they run restaurants?
- Well, so, my dad,
he was a chef for 35 years,
and trained his brothers,
- who were also chefs.
- Very nice.
All right, if you want an apron,
now's the time to step up.
- Are you ready?
- We're ready!
All right,
let's see who's the best!
Your time starts now!
- Thank you.
- Yes!
- Gordon: Let's go!
- Tina: Let's go Aivan.
- I'm coming, I'm coming.
- Let's cook.
- This is gonna be
an exciting battle.
- Yeah!
- Shanda, you need anything?
- I'm good, baby.
- Let's go.
- Extended family.
Sometimes that can get
a little complicated.
But in the kitchen?
Man, it's just fireworks, right?
I didn't really cook
a whole lot with my family.
- We kind of cooked separate
and brought things together.
- Sure.
But then when
we would get in the kitchen,
there was a lot of, like,
"No, no, no.
You don't make it this way,
you make it that way."
- Careful with the knife, baby.
- Will do.
Aivan and Tina,
give us an insight into
the dish you're making.
- We're making my grandma's
steamed bass with--
- Steamed?
- You need to speak up, honey.
- Oh.
- We cannot hear
nothing from you.
- Can you hear me over there?
She's got the big mouth,
not me.
We're making steamed bass
with glass noodles
- and black bean sauce.
- Gordon: Love that.
- Whereabouts is grandma from?
- From Vietnam.
In 1975, she immigrated to
the United States with my aunt,
uncle, and my mom.
So being here and representing
her and sharing our culture
- and heritage is crazy.
It's so special.
- I love that.
Brilliant. And, Tina,
now that you've retired,
- are you spending more time
in the kitchen cooking?
- Tina: Yes.
I spend a lot of time
in my kitchen.
Aivan:
All day every day.
Tina:
If you tell me to go cook,
I mean, I glow.
If you tell me to go do laundry,
no, that can wait till tomorrow.
- You're funny, by the way.
- She is the life of the party.
- I bet.
- Whoo!
- Toasting.
- Pistachios?
- Yep. Throw them in.
- I got you.
B-b-b-b-- that's it.
Yeah!
Shanda and Asa, what are you
preparing for us this evening?
We have a pistachio risotto
with duck breast
We have four uncles
that are chefs.
This is their spin
on the classic risotto.
And I think
it's important to note, Chef,
that our uncles, they weren't
classically trained,
but they learned on the job,
and they were trained by chefs
from France and northern Italy.
Working with great chefs
is really the road
to becoming a great chef.
100%.
We're from a huge family.
- Joe: Got it.
- Cooking is our rite
of passage.
So you're doubling down
on the jeopardy,
because you're making risotto,
which is very difficult enough.
Then you're gonna render
and sear a duck breast.
That's a tall order
in 30 minutes.
Well, we have a lot of
confidence in ourselves, chef.
And I believe that we'll be able
to get this done for you.
Tiffany: All right,
we're looking forward to it.
So we're 20 minutes down.
We have 10 minutes remaining.
- Let's go.
- Fish is in.
With that Vietnamese
steamed bass,
the cooking on the bass
it is very hard because
it's thick and dense.
But if they can pull that off,
then that could be a great dish.
- Gordon: Yeah.
- It's good.
- Aivan: Okay.
- How's the duck ducking?
- He ducking.
- ( Shanda laughs )
So Shanda and Asa are taking
two of the most difficult things
that we see throughout
the years here and putting
them on one plate?
I mean,
how do you make risotto
within 30 minutes?
- That's tough.
- Yeah.
Behind you. Behind you.
Right, how are we doing
with this risotto?
Shanda: It's coming along.
It's coming along.
How have you got the pistachios
in the risotto?
- What have you done?
- I chopped them down
and then I used a little butter.
How's that?
So you need a touch
more stock in there
so the kernels
can bloom and absorb that.
- Thank you, Chef.
- Okay, 'cause it's just
a little bit undercooked.
- Okay. Will do.
- Make sure that rice is cooked.
Keep tasting.
Six minutes to go guys. Yes?
- Okay. Thank you.
- You want to check it?
- Just look at it real quick.
- Excellent.
- You can turn it off.
Mm. Smells good.
- Okay.
Five minutes remaining.
Let's go!
- Shanda: Oh, boy.
- Asa: Talk to me, Shanda.
What you got?
I don't want
to lift the lid anymore.
I want it to cook.
Shanda and Asa, they've reduced
the stock so much,
it wasn't absorbing.
So the rice wasn't blooming,
and so it is dry.
It needs more liquid.
Gordon:
If they don't fix this fast,
they're gonna run out of time.
( groans )
I don't want to lift
the lid anymore.
I want it to cook.
How much more time do you
have left on your risotto?
- About three minutes.
- Hurry up and wait, baby.
Hurry up and wait.
- That's right.
- Okay, I'm gonna take the fish,
and then you're gonna season
the noodles a little bit for me.
Final two minutes.
Start thinking
about the plating.
How you feeling on that risotto?
All right, I'm ready to go.
Let's start plating, baby.
- Come on!
Finishing touches. Let's go!
- Ooh, look at that.
- Come on, come on, come on.
- We got it. We got it.
Five, four, three, two, one.
- Gordon: And stop.
Hands in the air.
- Joe: Hands up.
- Well done.
- Good job!
Joe: All right.
So, first up Aivan and Tina,
please bring us your dish.
Aivan: We made
my grandma's steamed bass
with black bean sauce,
glass noodles, and herb salad.
I love the elegance of this.
I'm dying to taste it
because it's got "eat me"
all over it.
Thank you.
It's glistening.
Fish is cooked beautifully.
And what you've done with
that ginger, it's delicious.
- Thank you.
- Thank you, Chef.
The noodles itself are perfect.
I will say though, I wish
that it had a little acid.
Whether that's
just a zest of the lime
to kind of perk it up...
- Yes.
- Tasting this dish
is like coming
to your house for dinner.
Full flavor, delicious.
Good job.
Welcome to my home.
My door always
open for you, Joe.
- Excellent.
- Okay, Joe!
- Thank you.
- Thank you very, very much.
The freshness of that,
that was lovely.
I love the idea of the lime.
All right, Shanda, Asa,
please bring us your dish.
Shanda: We present to you
a pan seared duck
with a pistachio risotto.
It's a dish
that's very inviting.
There's a lot of technique
that you put into this.
You're really doing
two dishes in one
because a risotto would
have been enough on its own.
- So I'm very eager to try it.
- Thank you, chef.
Shall we?
The duck is juicy.
It's seasoned beautifully.
But then you've got
the richness of that risotto.
It's a little bit too rich
and too heavy.
And the consistency, it's not
giving the true risotto texture,
but it's delicious.
- Okay. Thank you.
- Yes, Chef.
The duck is beautiful.
So much flavor.
Really well-seasoned.
You've allowed it to rest.
You've done all the right steps
to make the duck delicious.
- Thank you, Chef.
- Look, the flavor is
very rich and intense.
But the risotto was undercooked.
- Thank you both.
- Both: Thank you.
Thank you.
Good job.
Hold me tight.
Okay, the best dish
in this battle was cooked by...
Tina and Aivan!
- What?
- Congratulations.
- Run, run!
- Thank you, Gordon.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you so much.
- Thank you, Gordon.
- Well done.
- Tiffany: Shanda, Asa,
you should be really proud.
The the dish that you created
had lots of flavor.
Do not let this keep you down.
- Thank you.
- This was awesome.
Asa: Very disappointing.
It may not have been
what the judges wanted.
There's a lot of things
that we can improve on.
And we'll take everything
that they said to heart.
- ( screaming )
- Look what we got!
Brought us some good luck.
This is even better than
my wedding dress. Trust me.
I'm gonna wear this
to the day I die.
( squealing, cheering )
- Next up,
Timothy and Athena...
- ( gasping )
- ...versus Azu and Javier.
- Aah!
Azu:
We came here to win.
If I don't get that apron,
I'm gonna stop talking to him
for the rest of my life.
- Please, God.
- But we're gonna get it.
I mean, it's for sure.
- Oh, my God.
- Look at these!
This competition is fierce.
It's cutthroat.
We know it's gonna be tough,
but winning that prize money
would change our lives
tremendously.
- It's about to be
us right there.
- Yeah?
We're coming to win
that battle first,
- get that apron, and win
the rest of the competition.
- 100%.
Holy guacamole, baby!
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
I'm going to faint.
( squealing )
This is real. Oh, my God.
Good evening
to all four of you.
- Thank you, Chefs.
- Thank you.
- To my left,
please introduce yourselves.
- My name is Timothy.
This is my beautiful
wife Athena.
We just got married
and this is our honeymoon.
- Congratulations!
- Thank you very much.
- Hope it's worth it!
- It's definitely worth it.
- Definitely worth it.
- And where did you propose?
I proposed
in Huntington Beach
in California.
I told her to face the ocean
and put her hands up
And I turned around,
and I was like,
"Baby, what are you--"
- He was on one knee.
- That is amazing.
All right,
who we have over here?
- My name is Azucena.
- My name is Javier.
We have been divorced 14 years.
We're ex-couples, but we have
two things in common.
One is food,
and our son Santiago,
the love of our lives.
Since we divorced,
we decided that we were
gonna remain friends forever
for the well-being of our son.
And it's a promise that we made,
and thanks to that promise,
we can be here today.
You want to remember
why you got divorced?
Is that why you're here?
- ( laughing )
- Joe: So now--
- I mean, I like
Javier very much.
- Okay.
I know he can get on
my nerves, but--
and I can get particularly
on his nerves.
You two, put your fingers
in your ears now.
Oh, my God. I'm so sorry.
Joe:
Newlyweds and divorced.
- The two opposite ends
of the extreme.
- Yes, sir.
- Absolutely.
- Listen, if you want to earn
your white aprons,
we'd love to see food
that really reflects your bond.
Get it on the plate,
but put it on with love.
Understood?
- Yes!
- Your time starts now!
- Let's go!
- Oh, my God!
- This way. This way.
- Okay, this'll be fascinating.
- Yeah, it is.
- And with only one duo
going through,
it's definitely gonna end
in heartbreak.
I cannot be nervous,
but I'm a little nervous.
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'm good.
So you have the newlyweds
that are spending
- all their time together.
- Yes.
You have the divorced couple
who have been separated
for 14 years.
Obviously have a history
of cooking together.
- Who's got the advantage?
- Hmm. It's a tough one.
- I'd say the history.
- I agree.
- I don't know.
- No?
I think the fact
that they've been doing it,
they're in rhythm right now.
History over here
might repeat itself.
- True.
- Oh, baby.
- Yeah? I'm getting
the potato started.
- Hell, yeah.
Timothy, Athena,
what are y'all making?
we are making a rack
of curried lamb,
some creamy mashed potatoes,
and sweet asparagus.
Give me insight
in to the curry.
My wife is a curry queen.
She's making
the curry paste right now.
- In a half hour?
- Yes, sir.
- Oh, absolutely.
- Gordon: Wow.
- You curry in a hurry.
- Curry in a hurry.
- That's how we do.
- These for you, right here.
- Okay, thank you so much.
- Azu, Javier.
- Yes, Chef?
- What are y'all making?
- Chicken roulade stew.
- This is a chicken breast
with almonds and raisins...
...that we prepare
in weddings and funerals.
I have to say, considering
your complicated situation,
the irony is not lost on us.
So it's the marriage
and death dish.
Well, I think that
you're gonna like it, chef.
Guys, we're coming up
to halfway. 15 minutes gone.
- Ay, yi, yi.
- 15 minutes to go.
- ( speaking Spanish )
- Right.
- Ah.
Chef, don't get too close.
I don't want your jacket
to get stained.
No, it's all good.
Tell me about this sauce.
I want a texture that
is similar to like a "molito."
- Yes. What's in there?
- I'm working on it.
- No, Chef! No, Chef!
One minute please!
- Mmm.
Gordon:
And what's your sous chef doing?
The sous chef
is doing the chicken.
- Okay, good.
Where is the chicken?
- It's the oven right now.
Right.
Just over 10 minutes to go.
- Oh, my God.
I'm getting nervous.
- Lots of time.
You're fine.
Talk to each other.
Timothy and Athena.
- Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
- Hello, hello.
In love.
Is Athena your goddess?
- Yes, she is.
- Athena is the goddess
of what?
- Wisdom and war.
I'm here to fight.
- Oh!
- Yes, ma'am.
- Love it.
Tiffany:
It looks really good, y'all.
- And make sure
you season everything.
- Yes, chef.
Mm. Mm! Mm!
- 25 gone.
- Oh, my gosh.
Gordon: We're down
to our last five minutes.
Azu and Javier, it's funny
because they're
not talking as much.
I thought they would--
- Oh, my goodness.
- But she's making an amazing
sauce with those almonds,
tomatoes, and the raisins,
- and it tastes delicious.
- How we looking on the curry?
- Salt.
- Little bit?
- Oh, yeah. Yeah, yeah.
- Gordon: It smells good.
What do we smell?
The curry though?
Definitely smell the curry...
- Tiffany: Yeah.
- ( speaking Spanish )
- This has to be right.
- What's he doing now?
Is he gonna cook it twice?
Oh, no. He's cutting it
and cooking it again?
Joe:
I think that's a panic move.
That probably wasn't
their original plan.
And at this point,
if he's second-guessing
and gonna sear it in the pan,
there's a definite chance
it's gonna come out dry.
- Yeah.
- That might cost them
some real flavor points.
I'm not too sure
if Javier has got this.
He seems a little bit
distant right now.
- Yeah.
- Is there an argument
going on there?
( speaking Spanish )
Don't overcook
the chicken, guys.
- Javier: Totally fine.
- No, no. Not totally fine.
Not for me.
No, no, no, no, no.
No, no.
We are coming down
to our final 60 seconds.
One minute to go.
Start plating. Come on.
- Lamb, babe.
- Let's go!
( speaking Spanish )
Ten, nine,
eight, seven, six,
five, four, three, two, one.
- And stop. Well done.
- Hands up.
- Joe: All right.
- Gordon: Well done.
All right, Timothy and Athena,
please bring us your dish.
Timothy:
We made curried lamb chops,
creamy mashed potatoes,
candied asparagus,
and a mint chutney.
- Visually, it looks good.
- Thank you very much.
So the rack of lamb
needs to be pink right?
- Yes, sir.
- Gordon: And...
Mmm! Wow!
Gordon:
Absolutely beautiful.
Been waiting to hear
those words from you, Chef.
( squeals )
Lamb is cooked beautifully.
It's quite a rare
technique there,
to cook the lamb that perfectly
and coat it in a curry sauce.
That is a marriage
made in heaven.
That's harmony right there.
The finesse comes from her.
She's taught me
everything I know.
Definitely newlyweds here.
I mean, look at this.
It's very rare that people
can cook a rack of lamb
that perfectly.
Asparagus itself
is sort of where I feel like
the plate is lacking.
I know you said sweet asparagus,
but I'm not getting
the sweetness there.
- But you got the meat down.
- Thank you, Chef.
You know, I think that this dish
really represents the unity
and the love that you guys
share right now.
- Wow! Joe!
- Joe!
You may kiss the bride.
- Thank you.
- Good job, guys.
Azu, Javier, bring your plate
forward please.
Oh. What's going on?
This is just to bring
a little bit of the aroma
of the cinnamon.
Javier:
The dish we have made today
is a chicken roulade stew.
Azu: Which is a chicken breast
with almonds and raisins,
sauce from Oaxaca.
Visually, listen,
it's attractive.
Now I've been to Oaxaca,
but I've never seen
a stew that firm.
- Was that the intention?
- Yes.
We decided to make it
a little bit more condensed.
Gordon:
Let's taste it, shall we?
First off, the chicken's
cooked beautifully.
It's seasoned well.
The sauce is delicious.
But I would have preferred it
to be a little bit more liquid.
Just a little bit more relaxed.
Overall,
I think the flavors
are really nice.
The sweetness with
the saltiness of the plantains
works together really,
really well.
And, Javi, the chicken itself
is beautifully cooked.
I was very concerned because
I saw it go back in the pan.
I'm like, "Oh, my God.
It's chicken breast.
There's no skin.
There's no fat."
But you did a really good job
of making sure that
that was done right.
- Thank you, Chef.
The dish actually comes together
and eats really, really well.
An excellent effort.
For two people who have been
separated to come together
and to create something
like this is really
quite an accomplishment.
- Azu: Thank you so much.
- Thank you, Chef.
Thank you.
Please give us a moment.
When we get that apron.
- Are we in agreeance? Yeah?
- Yeah.
Hmm.
Okay, we felt the best dish
in this battle was cooked by...
Timothy and Athena.
It looks like the honeymoon's
gonna have to wait
a little bit longer, guys.
Way to go!
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you so much.
- Oh, here you go.
- Thank you.
Gordon:
Azu, Javier, there's something
quite dynamic about you two
and the passion you bring
to the kitchen.
That's obvious.
Such a shame, because
the chicken was delicious,
but the dish, it was just
a little bit too stiff.
- But thank you.
- Thank you.
Azu: I'm sad,
of course, but listen.
It has been a great experience
to share with Javier these days.
For me, it's already
a great gift.
And it just didn't happen,
but it's okay.
- ( cheering )
- Aah!
- Oh, my God!
- Yeah!
This has been an amazing year.
We just got married.
We marked that off.
MasterChef apron?
- Both: Marked that off.
- Next thing is the trophy.
Whoo!
So, that's three sets of aprons
down, five remaining.
And honestly, so far,
I am so impressed.
Next time on
"MasterChef: Dynamic Duos"...
Welcome, welcome, welcome.
- the audition battles
continue...
- Let's go!
as more home cook duos
go head-to-head...
Come on, Ash! Let's do it.
- We want that white apron.
- Nice flambe.
We're here to win.
We're taking 'em down.
...to try to secure a pair
of coveted white aprons.
You guys know
how to make a fire, right?
- You're about to get
extinguished.
- Rawr!
We really see the dynamic duo
in the dish.
And you're going to give us
an apron for it.
- It's a little messy.
- Joe: You really shot
for the stars.
- Here we go.
- And you just missed.
- Oh, boy.
- Oh, my God.